<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Rodrigo Souza&#39;s Den</title>
    <link>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Rodrigo Souza&#39;s Den</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Rodrigo Souza</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trends of stellar entropy along stellar evolution</title>
      <link>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/trends-entropy_raa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/trends-entropy_raa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cold Quark Matter in Nature: Theory and Observations</title>
      <link>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/phd_thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/phd_thesis/</guid>
      <description>The main goal of this work is the study of cold quark matter in neutron stars from phase transitions of hadronic matter to quark matter. In this work, after presenting important aspects of stellar evolution and the theory of neutron stars, we review two frameworks designed to calculate the structure of the stars in the relativistic regime: the canonical Tolman-Oppenheimer-Volkoff equations and the so called &#39;new paradigm&#39; Einstein-Maxwell-Fermi, where we conclude that the Einstein-Maxwell-Fermi model has some inconsistencies, being inadequate for the treatment of stars with hybrid equation of state, and the fact that using the atomic model as a starting point already has the property of the local non-neutrality as a built-in feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of stellar entropy</title>
      <link>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/entropy_astronomische_nachrichten/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/entropy_astronomische_nachrichten/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information theoretical methods as discerning quantifiers of the equations of state of neutron stars</title>
      <link>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/info_theoretical_eoss_pla/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/info_theoretical_eoss_pla/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing the parameter space for unparticle-inspired models using white dwarf masses</title>
      <link>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/unparticles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/unparticles/</guid>
      <description>More detail can easily be written here using Markdown and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Um processo de transformação de arquiteturas de sistemas legados baseado em Reengenharia</title>
      <link>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/msc_dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rodrigosouza.net.br/publication/msc_dissertation/</guid>
      <description>From the moment software products are delivered, they go through a series of modifications during their life-cycle. The maintenance process can either be corrective or evolutionary/adaptive. A corrective process is used to fix implementation errors and an evolutionary/adaptive process is used to improve performance and structure or other attributes, or to adapt the product to a changed environment, according to requests from users. When it comes to evolutionary maintenance, software reengineering plays a fundamental role, since working teams responsible for maintenance projects frequently do not have enough knowledge about the system they will be working with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>